Tolulope Babatunde

Full Stack Developer

39 Ondo street Bodija,

Ibadan, Oyo

Nigeria,

babatundetolulopejoshua@yahoo.com 07041147115

Passionate and talented developer with over 5 years experience in full stack development, with a particular interest in using javascript-based libraries and frameworks to create highperformance and user-friendly applications. Seeks a position where he can deliver exceptional user experience using the best front-end, back-end technologies and design principles.

Professional Experience

Full Stack Developer

Ehealth4everyone | July 2023 - Present

- Implement front-end components using JavaScript frameworks (React and Vue.js)
- Develop and maintain high-quality, responsive web applications
- Develop and manage well-functioning databases and APIs
- Create security and data protection settings
- Work with development teams and product managers to understand user requirements and provide technical solutions
- Ensure cross-browser compatibility and optimize applications for maximum speed and scalability
- Conduct code reviews and maintain high standards of code quality

Frontend Developer

Cytix IO | June 2022 - June 2023

- Build features and applications with responsive and appealing visual design
- Collaborate with designers to translate UI/UX design wireframes into code.

Full Stack Developer

Freelance | September 2019 - June 2022

- Develop and maintain back-end services and APIs using Node.js
- Write effective APIs for web applications
- Test software to ensure responsiveness and efficiency
- Create security and data protection settings

Education

B.Tech in Physics

Federal University of Technology at Akure | January 2010 - January 2015

Key Skills

- Knowledge of front-end languages and libraries (HTML/CSS, Javascript, Typescript, React, and Vue.js)
- Knowledge of multiple back-end languages (Node.js, Java Spring Boot)
- Familiarity with databases (MySQL, MongoDB), web servers and UI/UX design principles and tools (Figma, Adobe XD)
- Experience with version control systems (Git) and CI/CD pipelines
- Familiarity with cloud platforms (AWS, Azure, Google Cloud) and containerization (Docker)
- Excellent communication, teamwork and attention to details
- Excellent analytical and multitasking skills